# Hadi Lashkari Ghouchani

# **Software Engineer**

@ hadi.pro.dev@gmail.com

(437) 996-2022

O Toronto, Canada

github.com/hadilq

M medium.com/@hadilq.dev

in linkedin.com/in/hadilq

### **Summary**

A curious developer with over 17 years of experience in software development, where almost 7 years of his experience covers Android development, over 2 years covers teaching algorithms and programming in universities, and over 8 years covers academic and self-employed experiences while he was a student.

An Introvert person who has profound learning and contributing skills. A creative, value driven and passionate developer who enjoys doing math, solving problems and creating scalable, maintainable, testable and efficient apps to make the world a better place to live.

A person whose goal is to surround himself with creative, clever, motivative and happy persons, so he can continuously learn more and more

He's interested in decreasing build time, improving productivity of engineers by tooling, Functional Programming, Machine Learning, Type Theory, Math, etc. so constantly looking forward to learning related technologies to use in Mobile apps

### **Experience**

### Software Engineer

at MobileLIVE

Apr. 2021 - Present

O Toronto, Canada

MobileLIVE is a Canadian tech-service provider unifying people, technology, and business to accelerate digital transformation. Over this time, he worked in Bell Canada as a contractor. Bell Canada is subsidiary Bell Aliant provides services in the Atlantic provinces. It provides mobile service through its Bell Mobility (including Virgin Mobile Canada) subsidiary, and television through its Bell Satellite TV and Bell Fibe TV subsidiaries

- Introduced RFCs to make technical decisions and steps to applying on any new idea.
- Adding value by teaching and discussing SOLID principles, and best practices of modularization, feature flags, and monorepo, etc
- Raise and implement the idea of automatically cloning and building all the source code in the multi-repo setup to reduce version conflicts, and improve code visibility for debugging purposes
- Raise the need for Gradle Enterprise and Productivity Engineer in the team, which leads to be the one who setup the Gradle Enterprise in the project to improve the build time, and create the necessary tools.
- Investigate problems related to proxy and self-signed certificates in VPN networks, where by implementing a script to install them automatically increased the build count in GE dashboard by 164%

Technologies:

- Kotlin Coroutines / Mockk, Mockito, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Lane based branching strategy, Git submodule, CI/CD
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Gitlab, Jenkins, Slack, Branch.io, inVision, Dynatrace, etc.

### Staff Android Developer

at iFood

m Oct. 2020 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

iFood is an ambitious project to build an entire food delivery ecosystem for all around the world. Currently, it's the biggest food delivery in Brazil, Colombia and Mexico, with 50+ million apps installed on Android devices alone. The Android project is highly modularized to make it possible for 50+ developers working on it fast.

- Propose and implement composite build to handle dependency management in Gradle. It decreased the rebuild time while updating a library from more than 13 min to less than a minute
- Implement Android side of metadata project. Its purpose is gathering all information of our highly modularized Android/iOS projects in a dashboard along backend information.
- Propose and apply a concept to move out the legacy code from the root module. It decreased the rebuild time of freed up modules by 55%
- Wrap up external libraries to better handling panic situations.

### Technologies:

- Dagger 2, Room, Kotlin Coroutines, Moshi, WorkManager / Mockk, Robolectric, jUnit, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Gradle Enterprise
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Databricks, Firebase, Bugsnag, Logzio, etc.

## Senior Android Developer

at Letgo

m Oct. 2019 - Mar. 2021

Barcelona, Spain

Letgo is the biggest classified marketplace in Turkey with 15+ million apps installed on Android devices

## Mission:

- Improve the performance of loading feeds by at least a minute
- Fix multiple Memory leaks
- . Known as "The man who broke the escape room" to emphasize his ability to think out of the box
- - Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Room / Mockito, Espresso, Robolectric, Jacoco, Ktlint, Fastlane, etc.
- Agile, Sprint, Github Flow, CI/CD, Dynamic Feature Module Delivery
- Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Figma, New Relic, Firebase, Amplitude, etc.

# Lead Android Developer

at Sheypoor

m Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2019

O Tehran, Iran

Sheypoor is one of two lead classified marketplaces in Iran with 1.5+ million users per day, 13+ million

- Increase the number of users per day from 0.5+ million to 1.5+ million in a year.
- Technologies:
- Dagger 2, RxJava 2, Butter Knife, Greendao / Mockito, Espresso, Jacoco, etc.
- - Agile, Kanban, Git Flow, CI/CD / Pivotal Tracker, Github, Jenkins, Slack, Zeplin, et

# Senior Android Developer

m Sep. 2015 - Des. 2017

Myket is one of two lead app stores in Iran with over 8+ million users. TL;DR Mission: Starting TDD and installing Jenking's pipeline to handle CI/CD.

# Java and C# developer

at Soha System

Mar. 2015 - Aug. 2015

▼ Tehran, Iran

SOHA is formed to focus on solutions based on smart cards. TL;DR Mission: Implementing Android and

# **Article / Repository**

✓ 2022 Post: Logic Tree in Android
 ✓ 2022 Sample App: Molecule sample app to solve some scoping problems in Android development.
 ✓ 2022 Post: Reproducibility
 ✓ 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Are feature flags, build variants, and sample apps related concepts?
 ✓ 2021 iFood Engneering post: Modularization tip: optimize the Root Module.
 ✓ 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Happy Railway. An improvement for Railway Oriented Programming in Kotlin.
 ✓ 2021 Library: Happy is a library to auto-generate Kotlin code to make calling APIs more concise.
 ✓ 2021 ProAndroidDev post: Rutter Reporting is an idea to use Flutter as III and Rutt for the main project.

2020 POC: Rust Flutter Reactive is an idea to use Flutter as UI and Rust for the main project.
 2020 Make Log4k Multiplatform: Simple logging library for Android, iOS, Mac, etc.

M 2020 ProAndroidDev post: A/B Testing Myths

O 2020 Sample App: Provide a full implementation for a No-Framework Dependency Injection in Kotlin
 2020 Contributing on Λrrow Library: Λrrow is a library for Typed Functional Programming in Kotlin
 2020 Library: A Kotlin compiler plugin that generates trackable method

☑ 2020 Medium post: Save State By Using RxJava or Kotlin Flow ☑ 2020 Medium post: RxJava instead of LiveData in MVVM

🕠 2020 Library: A glue between the lifecycle of LifecycleOwner in Android and upstreams in RxJava

2019 Sample App: Functional Programming + Clean Architecture

 ☼ 2019 Sample App: Movie Challenge
 ☼ 2019 Math Library: Modularized, mathematical and multiplatform Kotlin library 

 \( \frac{\text{O}}{2}\) 2018 Log4k Library: Easy logging library, but unfortunately it's in Sheypoor repository

 \( \frac{\text{V}}{2}\) 2018 ProAndroidDev post: Reactive MVVM architectural pattern

2018 Sample App: Clean Architecture + RMVVM

2018 LiveEvent library: It's useful to propagate single event to View

# **Education**

Sharif University Of Technology Payame Noor University

M.Sc B.Sc

in Physics in Physics

🛗 Jul. 2007

O Tehran, Iran

Mashhad, Iran

## **Tools / Skills**

### Android

Partially Open Source Mobile Lifecycles/LiveData/Navigation/Paging/ViewModel Multidex/Test/Data Binding/WorkManager/Room Android Architecture Components/JetPack Anvil/Dagger 2/RxJava 2/Retrofit 2/.. Kotlin Multiplatform/Kotlin Coroutines Kotlin Compiler Plugin/KSP/. Compose/Data Binding/View Binding/...

Summary of why you're interested: It's partially open source OS. Generally interested on Mobile Technologies.

### Flutter

StatelessWidget/StatefulWidget StreamController/Isolates

Summary of why you're interested: Generally interested on all cross-platform and multi-platform solutions.

### Rust

tonic/prost/openssl/tokio/flatbuffers/thrift

Summary of why you're interested: Rust's type system is what you need for scale-up. Borrow Checker restrictly stops any memory leaks. Bevy, and Dioxus frameworks look like good candidates for cross-platform solutions.

### Nix

NixOS/Nix Darwin mkDrivation/mkShell

Summary of why you're interested: Reproducibility is the key to productivity.

### **Architecture**

Clean Architecture/Hexagonal Architecture Unidirectional data flow Architecture MVVM/MVI/MVP/RMVVM

### Principle

Clean Code/SOLID Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming Stable Dependencies Principle Stable Abstractions Principle

Factory/Builder/Singleton/...

### Adapter/Facade/Proxy/Visitor/Delegate/... Strategy/Chain of responsibility/...

Design Pattern

Android test library JUnit/Mockito/Espresso/Jacoco/...

# **Build Tool**

Gradle/Cargo/Sbt/Maven/Ant/Make/...

# **Command Line Tool**

grep/sed/netstat/awk/docker/... adb/sdkmanager/avdmanager/...

# **Development Tool**

Pivotal Tracker/Jira/Jenkins/Travis/CircleCi/...

### Java/Kotlin/Rust/Scala/Haskell/Python Groovy/Dart/Javascript/Ruby...

Programing Language

**Operating System** 

Linux(Nix OS/Fedora/Ubuntu/Debian), OS X

# Special Honor

- 2020 Had an offer from MobileLIVE, Toronto, Canada
- 2020 Had an offer from iFood, Remote 2019 Had an offer from Kik, Kitechener, Canada
- 2019 Had an offer from Letgo, Barcelona, Spain - 2019 Had an offer from CRITICAL Techworks, BMW, Porto, Portugal
- 2019 Had an offer from The Next Big Thing, Berlin,
- 2018 Received result-oriented badge in Sheypoor
- 2007 Ranked 44th among more than five thousand participants in the National Graduate Entrance Exam in

# Language

English: Advance Farsi: Native

The source of this resume is in github Built on October 28, 2022